<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alarm 4 on Russell Writes Code</title><link>/categories/alarm-4/</link><description>Recent content in Alarm 4 on Russell Writes Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 21:22:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/alarm-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alarm Development News</title><link>/2011/05/alarm-development-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 21:22:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/05/alarm-development-news/</guid><description>Hi all,
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a bit on Alarm 4 and Alarm 3.5.18, both of which are coming along nicely. I&amp;rsquo;m not quite ready for a v4.0 alpha release yet but I will be in the coming months.
It&amp;rsquo;s been really hard to work on Alarm in the past year or so as I&amp;rsquo;ve been working full time and juggling other facets of my life. I promise, however, that Alarm 4 will be released this year.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Update</title><link>/2010/12/alarm-4-update-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 15:48:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/12/alarm-4-update-2/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been making steady progress on Alarm 4, although I kinda got sidetracked by the huge bug in v3.5, so I&amp;rsquo;m currently shooting for an alpha by mid to late January. I should be able to at least button everything up enough to get it out to testers.
That&amp;rsquo;s all for now. Please join the Facebook fan group.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Update</title><link>/2010/11/alarm-4-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 23:04:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/11/alarm-4-update/</guid><description>Just thought I&amp;rsquo;d say a little bit about the ongoing Alarm 4 work that I&amp;rsquo;m doing.
Although it was put on the back burner there for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started working on Alarm 4 once again. I&amp;rsquo;m about 90% finished on the event system and I&amp;rsquo;ve completed the revamped playlist system. There is still a lot of UI work to be done but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start attacking that here in the next few days.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Still Coming, Alarm 3.5.12 Next Month</title><link>/2010/04/alarm-4-still-coming-alarm-3-5-12-next-month/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 01:42:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/alarm-4-still-coming-alarm-3-5-12-next-month/</guid><description>Yeah, so I kinda failed on the April 2 release date, but I have been actively developing Alarm 4 and it is coming along nicely. It&amp;rsquo;s just a huge project and I&amp;rsquo;ve been ridiculously busy with other aspects of my life. I have 2 out of the 3 main pieces pretty much wrapped up so the first test versions will be headed out soon (looking like May/June at this point).</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Roadmap</title><link>/2010/01/alarm-4-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 22:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/01/alarm-4-roadmap/</guid><description>Today I put together an aggressive roadmap to get Alarm 4 out the door by April 2. While the dates aren&amp;rsquo;t set in stone, I will be working diligently on meeting the dates that I have planned. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of my release goals:
Alpha 1: February 15, 2010 - Main design goals completed (Scheduler) Alpha 2: February 22, 2010 - Secondary goals completed (Startup, Wake from Sleep) Alpha 3: March 1, 2010 - Other goals completed (New update system, Theming, Media Search) Beta 1: March 8, 2010 - Bug Fixes, code cleanup Beta 2: March 15, 2010 - Bug Fixes, code cleanup RC 1: March 19, 2010 - Bug Fixes and Finalization RC 2: March 26, 2010 - Final Fixes and Changes 4.</description></item><item><title>Support, Download Links, Old Alarm Updates</title><link>/2009/12/support-download-links-old-alarm-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 18:18:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/support-download-links-old-alarm-updates/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve changed the main Alarm support email address.
You can now receive support by sending a message to: support@russellwritescode.com
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that in order to have a more consistent experience for those who would like to add a link to the Alarm installer on their website, I will have a permanent location for the latest version of Alarm. This location will always be available as long as this site is online so that download links will not be broken and people are guaranteed to get the absolute latest version of Alarm when they download it.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Fan Page on Facebook</title><link>/2009/11/alarm-fan-page-on-facebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 20:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/alarm-fan-page-on-facebook/</guid><description>If you like Alarm, please consider joining the fan page on Facebook.
Click Here to Visit Alarm @ Facebook
There you will get notifications of updates delivered to your news feed as well as the opportunity to directly interact with the developer. Suggestions are always welcome!</description></item><item><title>Work, Akron, and Other Stuff</title><link>/2009/07/work-akron-and-other-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/work-akron-and-other-stuff/</guid><description>So I’m working about 40 hours a week trying to get permissions done for one of SAY’s projects. In my spare time, I’m trying to play some Halo and work on Alarm 4. My last day of work before I make the move to Akron is July 31 which means I only have 10 days left. Yes.
I’m moving to Akron on August 8th. I start my research on network protocols on August 10th.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4.0 Development News, Alarm 3.5.9</title><link>/2009/06/alarm-4-0-development-news-alarm-3-5-9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 17:44:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/06/alarm-4-0-development-news-alarm-3-5-9/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m now hard at work on Alarm 4.0. This version includes many new enhancements, the most noticeable of which is the new scheduling system.
The system allows for the user to set multiple alarms with various means of notification. These include the classic system beep from Alarm 2.0-2.9, the single song functionality from Alarm 3.0/3.1, the playlist functionality from Alarm 3.5, and a new type of alert done by using the Windows system sounds.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.4 Released, Future Plans</title><link>/2008/11/alarm-3-5-4-released-future-plans/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 16:01:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/alarm-3-5-4-released-future-plans/</guid><description>Ok, Alarm 3.5.4 is code-complete and I&amp;rsquo;m planning on releasing it on Friday (or sooner) depending on any regressions or other bugs I find during the next few days. This version contains more bug fixes than I&amp;rsquo;d like to admit to, but here are the major ones:
Random playlist was not properly reordered after adding or removing items. Vista UAC and Limited Accounts. Should work now&amp;hellip;finally! Prevent Windows Update Restart shown on limited accounts even though it can&amp;rsquo;t be set on them.</description></item></channel></rss>