<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alarm 3 on Russell Writes Code</title><link>/categories/alarm-3/</link><description>Recent content in Alarm 3 on Russell Writes Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 20:03:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/alarm-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alarm Updates</title><link>/2016/06/alarm-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 20:03:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/06/alarm-updates/</guid><description>I was going to shut down the Alarm Update service today (after originally saying it would be taken offline back in April), and I realized that it hasn&amp;rsquo;t actually been working properly since I migrated my websites to Azure. So, I&amp;rsquo;ll give all the 3.5.18 and earlier users until August 18, 2016 to update, and then I&amp;rsquo;m definitely shutting it off. So, update to 3.5.19!</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.19 Released</title><link>/2016/01/alarm-3-5-19-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 01:28:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/01/alarm-3-5-19-released/</guid><description>Today, I officially released Alarm 3.5.19. You can get it on the &amp;ldquo;Things I Work On&amp;rdquo; page, or just Check for Updates in the application. This is the first official release of Alarm since July 2011, so there is a huge amount of changes (even though it is a minor revision).
This version contains several performance enhancements and large rewrites of core areas of the application. It also updates the Update Checker to the new RWC API.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.18 Released</title><link>/2011/07/alarm-3-5-18-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 02:03:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/07/alarm-3-5-18-released/</guid><description>Today, I officially released Alarm 3.5.18. You can get it on the downloads page, or just Check for Updates in the application.
This version adds the ability to save and load alarm times by the File menu. It also contains a couple other minor changes. Enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Development News</title><link>/2011/05/alarm-development-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 21:22:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/05/alarm-development-news/</guid><description>Hi all,
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a bit on Alarm 4 and Alarm 3.5.18, both of which are coming along nicely. I&amp;rsquo;m not quite ready for a v4.0 alpha release yet but I will be in the coming months.
It&amp;rsquo;s been really hard to work on Alarm in the past year or so as I&amp;rsquo;ve been working full time and juggling other facets of my life. I promise, however, that Alarm 4 will be released this year.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.17 Released</title><link>/2011/02/alarm-3-5-17-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 02:47:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/02/alarm-3-5-17-released/</guid><description>Today, I officially released Alarm 3.5.17. You can get it on the downloads page, or just Check for Updates in the application.
This version changes how easy it is to reset the alarm by accident by asking before it is reset. I have accidentally reset it in the morning and been late to work (my laptop is beside my bed), so hopefully this helps out all those out there who have had it happen.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.16 Released</title><link>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 15:37:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-released/</guid><description>Today I have released Alarm 3.5.16 on the site and via auto update. This version fixes a pretty serious bug that caused the Alarm to snooze/do quick alarm improperly if the 24 hour clock setting was set.
Download it on the downloads page or get it via auto update, especially if you use that setting.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.16 Delayed Until 12/10</title><link>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-delayed-until-1210/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 17:55:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-delayed-until-1210/</guid><description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to delay v3.5.16 for a few more days as my regression tests picked up another bug. I should be able to get it fixed and re-tested by Friday.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.16 Coming Soon</title><link>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-16-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 20:50:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-16-coming-soon/</guid><description>So while working on Alarm 4, I found an issue in the snooze/quick alarm functionality in v3.5.12-3.5.15. So, I will be releasing Alarm 3.5.16 on December 4. While I&amp;rsquo;ve already finished the bug fix, I am spending a great deal of time to test and make sure something like this doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen again.
It is a pretty serious bug, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect too many users. Basically, I found out that if you have 24 hour clock mode enabled and you snooze or use quick alarm between 12:00 and 23:59, the alarm time will be incorrect.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.15</title><link>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-15/</guid><description>Today one of my friends found a bug when two options are enabled together, so I fixed it and pushed out 3.5.15. Get it on the site or via auto update. Alarm 4 is still on it&amp;rsquo;s way.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.14</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 02:29:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14/</guid><description>I just put Alarm 3.5.14 up on the site. Upgrade to it ASAP if you were using 3.5.12 (see previous post for why).
Alarm 3.5.14 Download</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.14 Coming Soon</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 03:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14-coming-soon/</guid><description>So I just found a bug in 3.5.12 that I missed during my normal testing, which means I am pulling it from auto-update. Basically, the playlist doesn&amp;rsquo;t advance past the first song when the alarm is going off, meaning if you sleep through your first song (as I often do), you probably wont wake up and be late for work/school/whatever as I was this morning. I removed something that was serving a purpose that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to serve in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.12</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 02:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12/</guid><description>I just uploaded Alarm 3.5.12. Get it on the downloads page.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.12 RC 2</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 01:20:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-2/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the release candidate. This contains the Windows Media Player playback functionality. Test thoroughly, as I just wrote it an hour ago and it might not work properly.
Download Alarm 3.5.12 RC 2</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.12 RC 1</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-1/</guid><description>Hey everyone, I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t said a whole lot lately, but I have a release candidate of Alarm 3.5.12 ready for download. I need extensive testing done on it as I have made a ton of changes over the past 6 months, most of which haven&amp;rsquo;t been used a lot. So please email me if you have any issues with the RC by using the &amp;ldquo;Report Bug&amp;rdquo; link in the software.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.11 Released, Merry Christmas!</title><link>/2009/12/alarm-3-5-11-released-merry-christmas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 04:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/alarm-3-5-11-released-merry-christmas/</guid><description>I am pleased to be releasing Alarm 3.5.11. This version, while originally deemed a major update, has been downgraded minor update due to an overly-complicated migration process between 3.5.10 and 3.5.11. So, the new settings system is delayed for Alarm 4.0, as originally intended. Having the new system in earlier 3.5.11 builds though has allowed me to fix a few issues with the system.
Changes to 3.5.11 are as follows:</description></item><item><title>Support, Download Links, Old Alarm Updates</title><link>/2009/12/support-download-links-old-alarm-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 18:18:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/support-download-links-old-alarm-updates/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve changed the main Alarm support email address.
You can now receive support by sending a message to: support@russellwritescode.com
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that in order to have a more consistent experience for those who would like to add a link to the Alarm installer on their website, I will have a permanent location for the latest version of Alarm. This location will always be available as long as this site is online so that download links will not be broken and people are guaranteed to get the absolute latest version of Alarm when they download it.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Fan Page on Facebook</title><link>/2009/11/alarm-fan-page-on-facebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 20:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/alarm-fan-page-on-facebook/</guid><description>If you like Alarm, please consider joining the fan page on Facebook.
Click Here to Visit Alarm @ Facebook
There you will get notifications of updates delivered to your news feed as well as the opportunity to directly interact with the developer. Suggestions are always welcome!</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5 Support Extended</title><link>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-support-extended/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 21:47:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-support-extended/</guid><description>Today I noticed that a lot of people are still using pre-3.5.8 versions of Alarm so I decided to support those versions again. Please upgrade them to 3.5.10!</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.10 Bug?</title><link>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-10-bug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 17:54:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-10-bug/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received a report of a bug in Alarm 3.5.10 which causes the program to freeze when it is sounding and is switching between songs on the playlist. If anyone is dealing with this problem, please send an email to support@russellwritescode.com immediately with a description of your computer system specifications. Obviously I want to fix this as soon as possible.
Thanks.</description></item><item><title>Windows 7</title><link>/2009/09/windows-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 05:00:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/09/windows-7/</guid><description>Tonight, I will be installing Windows 7 Professional on my main computer. I’ve tried the release candidate and I really liked it so now is the time to get away from Vista. Although I like Vista, I know it’s all sluggish and such, and I haven’t reinstalled it since November 2008, so it’s time for the upgrade. I know it doesn’t come out until Oct 22, but I’m an early adopter.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.10 Released</title><link>/2009/08/alarm-3-5-10-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 04:24:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/08/alarm-3-5-10-released/</guid><description>Hey everyone, today I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.10. This version contains a couple of bug fixes to the app launcher and windows update functionality.
Go get it.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Update Coming Soon</title><link>/2009/07/alarm-update-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 15:01:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/alarm-update-coming-soon/</guid><description>I found a minor bug with Alarm 3.5.9 so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be releasing a 3.5.10 update soon. I&amp;rsquo;m testing it heavily to stamp out any other bugs I can find so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep maintaining this version.
That&amp;rsquo;s all for now. Look for that update soon.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.9 Released, Other News</title><link>/2009/07/alarm-3-5-9-released-other-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/alarm-3-5-9-released-other-news/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.9. This build is 99.9% the same as RC 2.
New features since 3.5.8 include:
Volume control - control the volume of Alarm separately from the system volume. Focus Time - choose whether the alarm time takes the place of the current time when the alarm is set. It is available from the update service for versions since 3.5 and will be made available for download from this site as soon as I complete this post.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.9 RC 2 Released</title><link>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-2-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 01:26:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-2-released/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.9 Release Candidate 2. This is only a minor update of the previous RC build.
This new release candidate version contains the option to focus the alarm time while the alarm is set. This was suggested by someone on download.com and I decided to add it to 3.5.9 after I realized that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be difficult at all.
Download Alarm 3.5.9 RC 2 Here (MD5: e30695fda4388c6065f98905c31acb55)</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.9 RC 1 Released</title><link>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 03:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-1-released/</guid><description>Today I am releasing a release candidate of Alarm 3.5.9. This version contains a change in the update system for Alarm 4 updating and a new feature which allows the user to set the volume for the application. Use it in conjunction with Test Volume to make sure your Alarm is at a reasonable level.
If no bugs are found, the release of Alarm 3.5.9 is planned for July 1. If you find any problems, please send me a message using the bug reporting address.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4.0 Development News, Alarm 3.5.9</title><link>/2009/06/alarm-4-0-development-news-alarm-3-5-9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 17:44:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/06/alarm-4-0-development-news-alarm-3-5-9/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m now hard at work on Alarm 4.0. This version includes many new enhancements, the most noticeable of which is the new scheduling system.
The system allows for the user to set multiple alarms with various means of notification. These include the classic system beep from Alarm 2.0-2.9, the single song functionality from Alarm 3.0/3.1, the playlist functionality from Alarm 3.5, and a new type of alert done by using the Windows system sounds.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.8 Released</title><link>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:17:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-released/</guid><description>I will be releasing Alarm 3.5.8 later today. This update includes several new things including:
Ability to Launch an Application when the alarm goes off. The Automatic Update Feature has now been updated to AUA v4 which is a completely re-written system which future versions will use. New &amp;ldquo;Alarm Off&amp;rdquo; button when the alarm is set, but not going off. &amp;ldquo;Turn Off&amp;rdquo; has been renamed to &amp;ldquo;Silence&amp;rdquo; Loads of refactoring done.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.8 RC 1 Released</title><link>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-rc-1-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 18:03:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-rc-1-released/</guid><description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m releasing a preview version of Alarm 3.5.8.
This version includes tons of cleaning up and refactoring and a couple of new features. More on them during the official release.
You can get the Release Candidate on the Downloads page.</description></item><item><title>Alarm News</title><link>/2009/04/alarm-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 03:57:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/04/alarm-news/</guid><description>So I spent most of today working on Alarm 3.5.8, which is coming along nicely. Most of the time was spent refactoring leftover code from v3 or v3.1 as well as just plain terrible code that exists for v3.5 only. Also in 3.5.8, there is a great new feature coming that one of my friends suggested. However, I do not want to spoil the surprise until the release date. I should be able to get that version out the door within about 2 weeks so look forward to that.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.7 Released</title><link>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-7-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 14:50:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-7-released/</guid><description>Ok, I&amp;rsquo;m not perfect. Alarm 3.5.7 was released today to fix a regression I introduced in 3.5.6. Whoops.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.6 Released</title><link>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-6-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 22:55:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-6-released/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.6. Download it from the website or from the auto-update service. This version contains 5 theme refreshes which should make them a bit easier on the eyes. Also, it contains about 2-3 bug fixes for bugs which have been there for a while.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.5 Released</title><link>/2009/03/alarm-3-5-5-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 15:25:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/alarm-3-5-5-released/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t realized it, I released Alarm 3.5.5 on February 27. Download it.</description></item><item><title>To Do List</title><link>/2009/02/to-do-list/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 05:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/to-do-list/</guid><description>I have many, many things to do this week. Just though I’d get it written down.
Get an eye exam and new glasses Clean up the room and car Sell some stuff on eBay Buy Halo Wars Get my two computers ready to be sold Release Alarm 3.5.5 and begin working on 3.6 Get the interrupt stuff done for senior design. So yeah, I will also be playing plenty of video games to pass my free time.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.4 Released, Future Plans</title><link>/2008/11/alarm-3-5-4-released-future-plans/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 16:01:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/alarm-3-5-4-released-future-plans/</guid><description>Ok, Alarm 3.5.4 is code-complete and I&amp;rsquo;m planning on releasing it on Friday (or sooner) depending on any regressions or other bugs I find during the next few days. This version contains more bug fixes than I&amp;rsquo;d like to admit to, but here are the major ones:
Random playlist was not properly reordered after adding or removing items. Vista UAC and Limited Accounts. Should work now&amp;hellip;finally! Prevent Windows Update Restart shown on limited accounts even though it can&amp;rsquo;t be set on them.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.3 Released, Alarm 3.1 End of Support</title><link>/2008/10/alarm-3-5-3-released-alarm-3-1-end-of-support/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 16:01:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/alarm-3-5-3-released-alarm-3-1-end-of-support/</guid><description>In Alarm 3.5.3, I have fixed about 7 bugs and added a new feature. I also added about 10 themes.
Also, as of today, Alarm 3.1 is no longer supported to be auto-updated to 3.5. There are way too many files to update every time I release a new version. If you&amp;rsquo;re using 3.1, you should have updated a long time ago!
As a final note, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that I&amp;rsquo;m up to 2800 downloads total among all the websites that host Alarm 3.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.2 Released</title><link>/2008/07/alarm-3-5-2-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 16:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/07/alarm-3-5-2-released/</guid><description>I should be releasing 3.5.2 this weekend with a playlist update and a single bug fix. Check for updates on Sunday.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.1 Released</title><link>/2008/06/alarm-3-5-1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/06/alarm-3-5-1-released/</guid><description>Ok, so today I released Alarm 3.5.1 which includes 2 bug fixes and a new feature called &amp;ldquo;Quick Alarm&amp;rdquo;. This version also adds support for unprotected WMA files.
Go get it!</description></item></channel></rss>