<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Russell Writes Code</title><link>/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on Russell Writes Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>/2020/02/site-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/02/site-updates/</guid><description>I wanted to spend a few minutes and update anyone out there listening on what I&amp;rsquo;m working on and how things are progressing in my life.
First of all, a couple status updates on some things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying are &amp;ldquo;coming soon&amp;rdquo; for about 10 years now:
Alarm 4.0
I&amp;rsquo;ve made a number of false starts to get the features I want in Alarm 4 developed and released to the community.</description></item><item><title>My Dog, Chuckie</title><link>/2014/03/my-dog-chuckie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 04:55:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/03/my-dog-chuckie/</guid><description>I spoke with my sister and dad on Monday night, and they told me that they had to put my dog, Chuckie, to sleep. I say &amp;ldquo;my dog&amp;rdquo; in the sense that for the last eight years, I didn&amp;rsquo;t live with him, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feed him, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take him outside when he needed it, but every single time I went home, I was the only person he was concerned with.</description></item><item><title>Follow me on Twitter!</title><link>/2013/05/follow-me-on-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 01:27:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/05/follow-me-on-twitter/</guid><description>I just opened a brand new Twitter account, so feel free to follow me.
@rwpcpe</description></item><item><title>New Blog</title><link>/2013/01/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 06:35:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/01/hello-world/</guid><description>This site is a major work in progress, but I decided to at least put it up. I&amp;rsquo;ll add things as I think of them, but the main goal is to post about the things that I enjoy: code, games, and TV.</description></item><item><title>Oh College</title><link>/2009/10/oh-college/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 05:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/oh-college/</guid><description>I’m really, really busy right now.
I just had two tests this past week, and I got a 94% (the highest grade in the class) on my Random Signal Analysis exam and an 80% on my Combinatorics and Graph Theory test. I’m really satisfied with my RSA score, not so much my CGT score.
I’m working on various research-related things right now which promise to absolutely destroy any chances at a life.</description></item><item><title>Windows 7</title><link>/2009/09/windows-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 05:00:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/09/windows-7/</guid><description>Tonight, I will be installing Windows 7 Professional on my main computer. I’ve tried the release candidate and I really liked it so now is the time to get away from Vista. Although I like Vista, I know it’s all sluggish and such, and I haven’t reinstalled it since November 2008, so it’s time for the upgrade. I know it doesn’t come out until Oct 22, but I’m an early adopter.</description></item><item><title>First 2 Weeks of Akron</title><link>/2009/08/first-2-weeks-of-akron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 04:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/08/first-2-weeks-of-akron/</guid><description>Well, I’ve been living here for a solid 2 weeks, and thus far, I’m really enjoying it. A major part of me misses little Ada but I think I will grow to enjoy this city. I haven’t started on any research type stuff, but I am learning to use the tools and learning the Python programming language, which is pretty fun.
Today, I wrote a tool to beat a game on facebook using Linux.</description></item><item><title>Work, Akron, and Other Stuff</title><link>/2009/07/work-akron-and-other-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/work-akron-and-other-stuff/</guid><description>So I’m working about 40 hours a week trying to get permissions done for one of SAY’s projects. In my spare time, I’m trying to play some Halo and work on Alarm 4. My last day of work before I make the move to Akron is July 31 which means I only have 10 days left. Yes.
I’m moving to Akron on August 8th. I start my research on network protocols on August 10th.</description></item><item><title>Contacts, Video Games, Etc.</title><link>/2009/03/contacts-video-games-etc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/contacts-video-games-etc/</guid><description>From now on, I will be most likely wearing contacts. I’ve been trying them out for the past few weeks and so far I really enjoy having them. I’ve actually become pretty good at putting them in and taking them out, which was my main problem last time I tried them.
My Xbox came back from the repair center so I took the Elite back to Walmart. Now my licenses won&amp;rsquo;t transfer back.</description></item><item><title>To Do List</title><link>/2009/02/to-do-list/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 05:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/to-do-list/</guid><description>I have many, many things to do this week. Just though I’d get it written down.
Get an eye exam and new glasses Clean up the room and car Sell some stuff on eBay Buy Halo Wars Get my two computers ready to be sold Release Alarm 3.5.5 and begin working on 3.6 Get the interrupt stuff done for senior design. So yeah, I will also be playing plenty of video games to pass my free time.</description></item></channel></rss>