<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog Posts on Russell Writes Code</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Russell Writes Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>/2020/02/site-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/02/site-updates/</guid><description>I wanted to spend a few minutes and update anyone out there listening on what I&amp;rsquo;m working on and how things are progressing in my life.
First of all, a couple status updates on some things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying are &amp;ldquo;coming soon&amp;rdquo; for about 10 years now:
Alarm 4.0
I&amp;rsquo;ve made a number of false starts to get the features I want in Alarm 4 developed and released to the community.</description></item><item><title>New in C# 7.0: Part 4 - Expression-Bodied Members</title><link>/2018/04/new-in-c-7-0-part-4-expression-bodied-members/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 23:00:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/04/new-in-c-7-0-part-4-expression-bodied-members/</guid><description>This week, we&amp;rsquo;re discussing Expression-Bodied Members in C# 7.0. Now, this was an existing feature in C# 6.0, but it was limited to only methods, like so:
public void DoAThingCS6() =&amp;gt; Console.WriteLine(&amp;quot;This is a test&amp;quot;); With the new additions in C# 7.0, we can now do Constructors, Deconstructors, and Properties. A Constructor definition looks like this:
public SomeClass() =&amp;gt; DoAThing(); Similarly, a Deconstructor looks like this:
~SomeClass() =&amp;gt; DoAThing(); Finally, although auto-properties are shorter, you can write properties with specific implementations with this new shorthand:</description></item><item><title>New in C# 7.0: Part 3 – Ref Returns</title><link>/2018/03/new-in-c-7-0-part-3-ref-returns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/03/new-in-c-7-0-part-3-ref-returns/</guid><description>Picking up where I left off last week, there&amp;rsquo;s another interesting new feature called &amp;ldquo;Ref Returns&amp;rdquo;. Similar to Ref Locals, this allows you to return a reference from a method, and then optionally use it as a Ref Local in the calling code.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the following method definition:
private static string[] strings = { &amp;quot;this&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;is&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;a&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;test&amp;quot; }; public static ref string GetSomeString(int number) { if (number &amp;lt; 0 || number &amp;gt;= strings.</description></item><item><title>New in C# 7.0: Part 2 – Ref Locals</title><link>/2018/03/new-in-c-7-0-part-2-ref-locals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 23:22:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/03/new-in-c-7-0-part-2-ref-locals/</guid><description>After about a year, I&amp;rsquo;m finally trying to start writing some more blog posts, so I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up right where I left off. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give a brief overview of Ref Locals.
Ref Locals allow you to create an alias for a variable so that you are not creating another copy of the data or reference (in the case of an object), in memory. In previous versions of C#, if you wanted to refer to a local variable with a different name, you&amp;rsquo;d have to do this:</description></item><item><title>New in C# 7.0: Part 1 - Out Variables</title><link>/2017/02/new-in-c-7-0-part-1-out-variables/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/02/new-in-c-7-0-part-1-out-variables/</guid><description>This is the first post in a series on the new features available in Visual Studio 2017 and C# 7.0. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about Out Variables.
One of the great new features is probably something you will use frequently, which is defining an out variable, and using that variable in the same statement. Currently, to use an out variable, one must do something like this:
DateTime dt; if (DateTime.</description></item><item><title>Hello, Ruby!</title><link>/2016/10/hello-ruby/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 02:19:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/10/hello-ruby/</guid><description>As part of my professional development plans for the year, I&amp;rsquo;m learning the Ruby language and the Ruby on Rails framework. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m just getting started so I&amp;rsquo;m a complete newbie, but here&amp;rsquo;s the first program that we all write when we&amp;rsquo;re learning a language: Hello, world!
I&amp;rsquo;m using the &amp;ldquo;irb&amp;rdquo; REPL command instead of actually saving source file(s) at this point. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I started:
def hello_world puts &amp;quot;Hello, world!</description></item><item><title>Alarm Updates</title><link>/2016/06/alarm-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 20:03:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/06/alarm-updates/</guid><description>I was going to shut down the Alarm Update service today (after originally saying it would be taken offline back in April), and I realized that it hasn&amp;rsquo;t actually been working properly since I migrated my websites to Azure. So, I&amp;rsquo;ll give all the 3.5.18 and earlier users until August 18, 2016 to update, and then I&amp;rsquo;m definitely shutting it off. So, update to 3.5.19!</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.19 Released</title><link>/2016/01/alarm-3-5-19-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 01:28:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/01/alarm-3-5-19-released/</guid><description>Today, I officially released Alarm 3.5.19. You can get it on the &amp;ldquo;Things I Work On&amp;rdquo; page, or just Check for Updates in the application. This is the first official release of Alarm since July 2011, so there is a huge amount of changes (even though it is a minor revision).
This version contains several performance enhancements and large rewrites of core areas of the application. It also updates the Update Checker to the new RWC API.</description></item><item><title>WCF: Logging All SOAP Messages</title><link>/2015/02/wcf-logging-all-soap-messages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:18:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/02/wcf-logging-all-soap-messages/</guid><description>Do you want to know what is actually in that SOAP message that your Windows Communication Foundation service is sending? Well, look no further. It&amp;rsquo;s actually quite simple to output the XML that is being created.
First, there are a couple classes that need to be added to your service project (or a separate project). The first of these is perhaps the most important, which is the message inspector that is used to do the actual logging, etc.</description></item><item><title>Supporting iPhone 6/6 Plus Native Resolutions: The Basics</title><link>/2014/11/iphone-66-plus-native-resolutions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 16:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/11/iphone-66-plus-native-resolutions/</guid><description>Ever since I got the new iPhone 6, I&amp;rsquo;ve been silently cursing the applications that haven&amp;rsquo;t yet properly updated their apps for the new screen sizes. The zoomed iPhone 5s display looks really terrible, folks! So, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give you a five minute tutorial to update your applications. Assuming, of course, that you updated your app last year for iOS 7. I&amp;rsquo;m also assuming that you have a reasonable understanding of how to navigate Xcode, so this post is a bit light on screenshots.</description></item><item><title>iOS 8: Notifications Changes</title><link>/2014/09/ios-8-notifications-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 04:04:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/09/ios-8-notifications-changes/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re updating our iOS application at work, and I came across some fun with iOS 8 and notifications. So, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a short post about it.
In iOS 7, we used the following method on the shared UIApplication instance to set up notifications:
[[UIApplication sharedApplication] registerForRemoteNotificationTypes:( UIRemoteNotificationTypeAlert | UIRemoteNotificationTypeBadge | UIRemoteNotificationTypeSound )]; In iOS 8, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. So now, it&amp;rsquo;s a multi-step process:
UIApplication *application = [UIApplication sharedApplication]; UIUserNotificationSettings *settings = [UIUserNotificationSettings settingsForTypes:(UIUserNotificationTypeAlert | UIUserNotificationTypeBadge | UIUserNotificationTypeSound) categories:nil]; [application registerUserNotificationSettings:settings]; [application registerForRemoteNotifications]; First, we get an instance of the shared UIApplication (this is obviously optional, but I think it makes the code easier to read).</description></item><item><title>GIT, Powershell, and Windows 8.1</title><link>/2014/05/git-powershell-and-windows-8-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 19:28:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/05/git-powershell-and-windows-8-1/</guid><description>This weekend I opted to upgrade(depending on your opinion) my laptop to Windows 8.1. Now that I have lost all credibility, I can move on to talk about my experience with using GIT on Windows 8.1, and the issue I had with my PowerShell profile script.
Like many users, I have a profile script set up in PowerShell so that when I open it, my main code directory is the working directory, and I also have a custom prompt set up to tell me the current folder&amp;rsquo;s GIT status.</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Builder</title><link>/2014/04/pattern-of-the-week-builder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 04:01:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/04/pattern-of-the-week-builder/</guid><description>This post is part of a series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Creational
This week&amp;rsquo;s pattern is called the Builder pattern. The builder pattern is a common way to create an object, using methods and properties to set up exactly the kind of object you want, then calling a Build() method to actually create the object.</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Prototype</title><link>/2014/03/pattern-of-the-week-prototype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 05:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/03/pattern-of-the-week-prototype/</guid><description>This is the seventh in a series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Creational
This week&amp;rsquo;s pattern is called the Prototype pattern. This pattern is used when you need to create exact copies of objects. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at our example Prototype class:
public class StreetSign { public StreetSign(string shape, string text) { Shape = shape; Text = text; } public string Text { get; private set; } public string Shape { get; private set; } public StreetSign Clone() { return new StreetSign(Shape, Text); } } This StreetSign class has two properties - Text and Shape, and a method called Clone.</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Proxy</title><link>/2014/03/pattern-of-the-week-proxy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 05:03:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/03/pattern-of-the-week-proxy/</guid><description>This is the sixth in a series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Structural
This week&amp;rsquo;s pattern is called the Proxy pattern. This pattern is primarily used to add security or to implement caching for objects. For my example, I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding security to this class:
public class SomeService : ISomeService { public List&amp;lt;string&amp;gt; GetStrings() { return new List&amp;lt;string&amp;gt; { &amp;quot;String1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;String2&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;String3&amp;quot; }; } } This is a pretty simple class, which implements the following interface:</description></item><item><title>My Dog, Chuckie</title><link>/2014/03/my-dog-chuckie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 04:55:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/03/my-dog-chuckie/</guid><description>I spoke with my sister and dad on Monday night, and they told me that they had to put my dog, Chuckie, to sleep. I say &amp;ldquo;my dog&amp;rdquo; in the sense that for the last eight years, I didn&amp;rsquo;t live with him, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feed him, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take him outside when he needed it, but every single time I went home, I was the only person he was concerned with.</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Abstract Factory</title><link>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-abstract-factory/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 04:42:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-abstract-factory/</guid><description>This is the fifth in a series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Creational
This week&amp;rsquo;s pattern is the Abstract Factory pattern. To explain this, we must first understand the factory class.
Factories create things, plain and simple. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re talking about software development or retail, that is what they do. Factory classes typically look something like this:</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Template Method</title><link>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-template-method/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 03:44:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-template-method/</guid><description>This is the fourth in a series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Behavioral
This week&amp;rsquo;s pattern is the Template Method pattern. This pattern allows you to define a set of algorithms that follow the same procedure, but that might have certain parts that differ. For this pattern, I&amp;rsquo;m borrowing heavily from my post on the Strategy Pattern, so if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it yet, you should read that one first.</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Strategy</title><link>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-strategy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 03:31:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-strategy/</guid><description>This is the third in a series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Behavioral
Difficulty: Beginner
This week&amp;rsquo;s pattern is the Strategy pattern. This pattern can be used when you have a set of similar algorithms. The easiest way to explain it is with an example, so let&amp;rsquo;s look at the following class:</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Decorator</title><link>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-decorator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 02:13:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/02/pattern-of-the-week-decorator/</guid><description>This is the second in a (hopefully) long series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Structural
Difficulty: Beginner
This week&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; is the Decorator pattern. To explain this pattern, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with an explanation of the Open/Closed Principle. The Open/Closed Principle is one of the five &amp;ldquo;SOLID&amp;rdquo; principles outlined by Robert C.</description></item><item><title>Pattern of the Week: Singleton</title><link>/2014/01/pattern-of-the-week-singleton/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 20:58:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/01/pattern-of-the-week-singleton/</guid><description>This is the first in a (hopefully) long series of &amp;ldquo;Pattern of the Week&amp;rdquo; posts. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily sticking with the Gang of Four patterns, but I may branch off occasionally. Thanks for reading.
Type: Creational
Difficulty: Beginner
Singleton. It is probably the least complicated of all design patterns, yet it can be confusing for beginners. In this post, I will attempt to explain exactly how to create a Singleton, talk about common implementation problems, and provide some sample code so you can see it in action.</description></item><item><title>SQL Server: Divide Date Range into Months</title><link>/2013/11/sql-server-divide-date-range-into-months/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 21:31:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/11/sql-server-divide-date-range-into-months/</guid><description>I wrote a script the other day that is utterly useless to me, but it might be helpful for someone else, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick post about it.
Suppose you have some date range, let&amp;rsquo;s say &amp;ldquo;1/20/2013 - 4/29/2014&amp;rdquo;. Now, suppose you want this range to be broken up into one month sections, with a start and end date for each month. Suppose, for some reason, you want to use a recursive common table expression (CTE).</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who - 50th Anniversary Trailer</title><link>/2013/08/doctor-who-50th-anniversary-trailer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/08/doctor-who-50th-anniversary-trailer/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge Doctor Who fan, and with the 50th Anniversary coming up on November 23rd, I thought I would post this fan-made trailer. It gets me really excited about November.
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rrSaTHsHNsc</description></item><item><title>Team Foundation Service: How do I delete a Team Project?</title><link>/2013/06/team-foundation-service-how-do-i-delete-a-team-project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 21:41:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/06/team-foundation-service-how-do-i-delete-a-team-project/</guid><description>I came across this problem earlier today, and I realized that it isn&amp;rsquo;t clear how to delete a team project. It is, however, really easy.
All you have to do is open the &amp;ldquo;Developer Command Prompt for VS2012&amp;rdquo; (located in Start &amp;gt; All Programs &amp;gt; Microsoft Visual Studio 2012 &amp;gt; Visual Studio Tools) and type the following command (assuming you have the server mapped in Visual Studio).
TfsDeleteProject /force /collection:https://ID.visualstudio.com/DefaultCollection PROJECT</description></item><item><title>Follow me on Twitter!</title><link>/2013/05/follow-me-on-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 01:27:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/05/follow-me-on-twitter/</guid><description>I just opened a brand new Twitter account, so feel free to follow me.
@rwpcpe</description></item><item><title>New Blog</title><link>/2013/01/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 06:35:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/01/hello-world/</guid><description>This site is a major work in progress, but I decided to at least put it up. I&amp;rsquo;ll add things as I think of them, but the main goal is to post about the things that I enjoy: code, games, and TV.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.18 Released</title><link>/2011/07/alarm-3-5-18-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 02:03:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/07/alarm-3-5-18-released/</guid><description>Today, I officially released Alarm 3.5.18. You can get it on the downloads page, or just Check for Updates in the application.
This version adds the ability to save and load alarm times by the File menu. It also contains a couple other minor changes. Enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Development News</title><link>/2011/05/alarm-development-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 21:22:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/05/alarm-development-news/</guid><description>Hi all,
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a bit on Alarm 4 and Alarm 3.5.18, both of which are coming along nicely. I&amp;rsquo;m not quite ready for a v4.0 alpha release yet but I will be in the coming months.
It&amp;rsquo;s been really hard to work on Alarm in the past year or so as I&amp;rsquo;ve been working full time and juggling other facets of my life. I promise, however, that Alarm 4 will be released this year.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.17 Released</title><link>/2011/02/alarm-3-5-17-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 02:47:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/02/alarm-3-5-17-released/</guid><description>Today, I officially released Alarm 3.5.17. You can get it on the downloads page, or just Check for Updates in the application.
This version changes how easy it is to reset the alarm by accident by asking before it is reset. I have accidentally reset it in the morning and been late to work (my laptop is beside my bed), so hopefully this helps out all those out there who have had it happen.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Update</title><link>/2010/12/alarm-4-update-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 15:48:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/12/alarm-4-update-2/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been making steady progress on Alarm 4, although I kinda got sidetracked by the huge bug in v3.5, so I&amp;rsquo;m currently shooting for an alpha by mid to late January. I should be able to at least button everything up enough to get it out to testers.
That&amp;rsquo;s all for now. Please join the Facebook fan group.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.16 Released</title><link>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 15:37:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-released/</guid><description>Today I have released Alarm 3.5.16 on the site and via auto update. This version fixes a pretty serious bug that caused the Alarm to snooze/do quick alarm improperly if the 24 hour clock setting was set.
Download it on the downloads page or get it via auto update, especially if you use that setting.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.16 Delayed Until 12/10</title><link>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-delayed-until-1210/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 17:55:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/12/alarm-3-5-16-delayed-until-1210/</guid><description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to delay v3.5.16 for a few more days as my regression tests picked up another bug. I should be able to get it fixed and re-tested by Friday.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.16 Coming Soon</title><link>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-16-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 20:50:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-16-coming-soon/</guid><description>So while working on Alarm 4, I found an issue in the snooze/quick alarm functionality in v3.5.12-3.5.15. So, I will be releasing Alarm 3.5.16 on December 4. While I&amp;rsquo;ve already finished the bug fix, I am spending a great deal of time to test and make sure something like this doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen again.
It is a pretty serious bug, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect too many users. Basically, I found out that if you have 24 hour clock mode enabled and you snooze or use quick alarm between 12:00 and 23:59, the alarm time will be incorrect.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Update</title><link>/2010/11/alarm-4-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 23:04:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/11/alarm-4-update/</guid><description>Just thought I&amp;rsquo;d say a little bit about the ongoing Alarm 4 work that I&amp;rsquo;m doing.
Although it was put on the back burner there for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started working on Alarm 4 once again. I&amp;rsquo;m about 90% finished on the event system and I&amp;rsquo;ve completed the revamped playlist system. There is still a lot of UI work to be done but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start attacking that here in the next few days.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.15</title><link>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/11/alarm-3-5-15/</guid><description>Today one of my friends found a bug when two options are enabled together, so I fixed it and pushed out 3.5.15. Get it on the site or via auto update. Alarm 4 is still on it&amp;rsquo;s way.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.14</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 02:29:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14/</guid><description>I just put Alarm 3.5.14 up on the site. Upgrade to it ASAP if you were using 3.5.12 (see previous post for why).
Alarm 3.5.14 Download</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.14 Coming Soon</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 03:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-14-coming-soon/</guid><description>So I just found a bug in 3.5.12 that I missed during my normal testing, which means I am pulling it from auto-update. Basically, the playlist doesn&amp;rsquo;t advance past the first song when the alarm is going off, meaning if you sleep through your first song (as I often do), you probably wont wake up and be late for work/school/whatever as I was this morning. I removed something that was serving a purpose that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to serve in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.12</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 02:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12/</guid><description>I just uploaded Alarm 3.5.12. Get it on the downloads page.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.12 RC 2</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 01:20:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-2/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the release candidate. This contains the Windows Media Player playback functionality. Test thoroughly, as I just wrote it an hour ago and it might not work properly.
Download Alarm 3.5.12 RC 2</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.12 RC 1</title><link>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/alarm-3-5-12-rc-1/</guid><description>Hey everyone, I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t said a whole lot lately, but I have a release candidate of Alarm 3.5.12 ready for download. I need extensive testing done on it as I have made a ton of changes over the past 6 months, most of which haven&amp;rsquo;t been used a lot. So please email me if you have any issues with the RC by using the &amp;ldquo;Report Bug&amp;rdquo; link in the software.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Still Coming, Alarm 3.5.12 Next Month</title><link>/2010/04/alarm-4-still-coming-alarm-3-5-12-next-month/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 01:42:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/alarm-4-still-coming-alarm-3-5-12-next-month/</guid><description>Yeah, so I kinda failed on the April 2 release date, but I have been actively developing Alarm 4 and it is coming along nicely. It&amp;rsquo;s just a huge project and I&amp;rsquo;ve been ridiculously busy with other aspects of my life. I have 2 out of the 3 main pieces pretty much wrapped up so the first test versions will be headed out soon (looking like May/June at this point).</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4 Roadmap</title><link>/2010/01/alarm-4-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 22:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/01/alarm-4-roadmap/</guid><description>Today I put together an aggressive roadmap to get Alarm 4 out the door by April 2. While the dates aren&amp;rsquo;t set in stone, I will be working diligently on meeting the dates that I have planned. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of my release goals:
Alpha 1: February 15, 2010 - Main design goals completed (Scheduler) Alpha 2: February 22, 2010 - Secondary goals completed (Startup, Wake from Sleep) Alpha 3: March 1, 2010 - Other goals completed (New update system, Theming, Media Search) Beta 1: March 8, 2010 - Bug Fixes, code cleanup Beta 2: March 15, 2010 - Bug Fixes, code cleanup RC 1: March 19, 2010 - Bug Fixes and Finalization RC 2: March 26, 2010 - Final Fixes and Changes 4.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.11 Released, Merry Christmas!</title><link>/2009/12/alarm-3-5-11-released-merry-christmas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 04:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/alarm-3-5-11-released-merry-christmas/</guid><description>I am pleased to be releasing Alarm 3.5.11. This version, while originally deemed a major update, has been downgraded minor update due to an overly-complicated migration process between 3.5.10 and 3.5.11. So, the new settings system is delayed for Alarm 4.0, as originally intended. Having the new system in earlier 3.5.11 builds though has allowed me to fix a few issues with the system.
Changes to 3.5.11 are as follows:</description></item><item><title>Support, Download Links, Old Alarm Updates</title><link>/2009/12/support-download-links-old-alarm-updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 18:18:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/support-download-links-old-alarm-updates/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve changed the main Alarm support email address.
You can now receive support by sending a message to: support@russellwritescode.com
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that in order to have a more consistent experience for those who would like to add a link to the Alarm installer on their website, I will have a permanent location for the latest version of Alarm. This location will always be available as long as this site is online so that download links will not be broken and people are guaranteed to get the absolute latest version of Alarm when they download it.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Fan Page on Facebook</title><link>/2009/11/alarm-fan-page-on-facebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 20:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/alarm-fan-page-on-facebook/</guid><description>If you like Alarm, please consider joining the fan page on Facebook.
Click Here to Visit Alarm @ Facebook
There you will get notifications of updates delivered to your news feed as well as the opportunity to directly interact with the developer. Suggestions are always welcome!</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5 Support Extended</title><link>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-support-extended/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 21:47:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-support-extended/</guid><description>Today I noticed that a lot of people are still using pre-3.5.8 versions of Alarm so I decided to support those versions again. Please upgrade them to 3.5.10!</description></item><item><title>Oh College</title><link>/2009/10/oh-college/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 05:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/oh-college/</guid><description>I’m really, really busy right now.
I just had two tests this past week, and I got a 94% (the highest grade in the class) on my Random Signal Analysis exam and an 80% on my Combinatorics and Graph Theory test. I’m really satisfied with my RSA score, not so much my CGT score.
I’m working on various research-related things right now which promise to absolutely destroy any chances at a life.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.10 Bug?</title><link>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-10-bug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 17:54:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/alarm-3-5-10-bug/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received a report of a bug in Alarm 3.5.10 which causes the program to freeze when it is sounding and is switching between songs on the playlist. If anyone is dealing with this problem, please send an email to support@russellwritescode.com immediately with a description of your computer system specifications. Obviously I want to fix this as soon as possible.
Thanks.</description></item><item><title>Windows 7</title><link>/2009/09/windows-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 05:00:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/09/windows-7/</guid><description>Tonight, I will be installing Windows 7 Professional on my main computer. I’ve tried the release candidate and I really liked it so now is the time to get away from Vista. Although I like Vista, I know it’s all sluggish and such, and I haven’t reinstalled it since November 2008, so it’s time for the upgrade. I know it doesn’t come out until Oct 22, but I’m an early adopter.</description></item><item><title>First 2 Weeks of Akron</title><link>/2009/08/first-2-weeks-of-akron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 04:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/08/first-2-weeks-of-akron/</guid><description>Well, I’ve been living here for a solid 2 weeks, and thus far, I’m really enjoying it. A major part of me misses little Ada but I think I will grow to enjoy this city. I haven’t started on any research type stuff, but I am learning to use the tools and learning the Python programming language, which is pretty fun.
Today, I wrote a tool to beat a game on facebook using Linux.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.10 Released</title><link>/2009/08/alarm-3-5-10-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 04:24:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/08/alarm-3-5-10-released/</guid><description>Hey everyone, today I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.10. This version contains a couple of bug fixes to the app launcher and windows update functionality.
Go get it.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Update Coming Soon</title><link>/2009/07/alarm-update-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 15:01:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/alarm-update-coming-soon/</guid><description>I found a minor bug with Alarm 3.5.9 so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be releasing a 3.5.10 update soon. I&amp;rsquo;m testing it heavily to stamp out any other bugs I can find so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep maintaining this version.
That&amp;rsquo;s all for now. Look for that update soon.</description></item><item><title>Work, Akron, and Other Stuff</title><link>/2009/07/work-akron-and-other-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/work-akron-and-other-stuff/</guid><description>So I’m working about 40 hours a week trying to get permissions done for one of SAY’s projects. In my spare time, I’m trying to play some Halo and work on Alarm 4. My last day of work before I make the move to Akron is July 31 which means I only have 10 days left. Yes.
I’m moving to Akron on August 8th. I start my research on network protocols on August 10th.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.9 Released, Other News</title><link>/2009/07/alarm-3-5-9-released-other-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/alarm-3-5-9-released-other-news/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.9. This build is 99.9% the same as RC 2.
New features since 3.5.8 include:
Volume control - control the volume of Alarm separately from the system volume. Focus Time - choose whether the alarm time takes the place of the current time when the alarm is set. It is available from the update service for versions since 3.5 and will be made available for download from this site as soon as I complete this post.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.9 RC 2 Released</title><link>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-2-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 01:26:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-2-released/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.9 Release Candidate 2. This is only a minor update of the previous RC build.
This new release candidate version contains the option to focus the alarm time while the alarm is set. This was suggested by someone on download.com and I decided to add it to 3.5.9 after I realized that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be difficult at all.
Download Alarm 3.5.9 RC 2 Here (MD5: e30695fda4388c6065f98905c31acb55)</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.9 RC 1 Released</title><link>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 03:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/06/alarm-3-5-9-rc-1-released/</guid><description>Today I am releasing a release candidate of Alarm 3.5.9. This version contains a change in the update system for Alarm 4 updating and a new feature which allows the user to set the volume for the application. Use it in conjunction with Test Volume to make sure your Alarm is at a reasonable level.
If no bugs are found, the release of Alarm 3.5.9 is planned for July 1. If you find any problems, please send me a message using the bug reporting address.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 4.0 Development News, Alarm 3.5.9</title><link>/2009/06/alarm-4-0-development-news-alarm-3-5-9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 17:44:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/06/alarm-4-0-development-news-alarm-3-5-9/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m now hard at work on Alarm 4.0. This version includes many new enhancements, the most noticeable of which is the new scheduling system.
The system allows for the user to set multiple alarms with various means of notification. These include the classic system beep from Alarm 2.0-2.9, the single song functionality from Alarm 3.0/3.1, the playlist functionality from Alarm 3.5, and a new type of alert done by using the Windows system sounds.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.8 Released</title><link>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:17:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-released/</guid><description>I will be releasing Alarm 3.5.8 later today. This update includes several new things including:
Ability to Launch an Application when the alarm goes off. The Automatic Update Feature has now been updated to AUA v4 which is a completely re-written system which future versions will use. New &amp;ldquo;Alarm Off&amp;rdquo; button when the alarm is set, but not going off. &amp;ldquo;Turn Off&amp;rdquo; has been renamed to &amp;ldquo;Silence&amp;rdquo; Loads of refactoring done.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.8 RC 1 Released</title><link>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-rc-1-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 18:03:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/alarm-3-5-8-rc-1-released/</guid><description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m releasing a preview version of Alarm 3.5.8.
This version includes tons of cleaning up and refactoring and a couple of new features. More on them during the official release.
You can get the Release Candidate on the Downloads page.</description></item><item><title>Alarm News</title><link>/2009/04/alarm-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 03:57:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/04/alarm-news/</guid><description>So I spent most of today working on Alarm 3.5.8, which is coming along nicely. Most of the time was spent refactoring leftover code from v3 or v3.1 as well as just plain terrible code that exists for v3.5 only. Also in 3.5.8, there is a great new feature coming that one of my friends suggested. However, I do not want to spoil the surprise until the release date. I should be able to get that version out the door within about 2 weeks so look forward to that.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.7 Released</title><link>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-7-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 14:50:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-7-released/</guid><description>Ok, I&amp;rsquo;m not perfect. Alarm 3.5.7 was released today to fix a regression I introduced in 3.5.6. Whoops.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.6 Released</title><link>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-6-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 22:55:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/04/alarm-3-5-6-released/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m releasing Alarm 3.5.6. Download it from the website or from the auto-update service. This version contains 5 theme refreshes which should make them a bit easier on the eyes. Also, it contains about 2-3 bug fixes for bugs which have been there for a while.</description></item><item><title>Contacts, Video Games, Etc.</title><link>/2009/03/contacts-video-games-etc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/contacts-video-games-etc/</guid><description>From now on, I will be most likely wearing contacts. I’ve been trying them out for the past few weeks and so far I really enjoy having them. I’ve actually become pretty good at putting them in and taking them out, which was my main problem last time I tried them.
My Xbox came back from the repair center so I took the Elite back to Walmart. Now my licenses won&amp;rsquo;t transfer back.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.5 Released</title><link>/2009/03/alarm-3-5-5-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 15:25:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/alarm-3-5-5-released/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t realized it, I released Alarm 3.5.5 on February 27. Download it.</description></item><item><title>Why me?</title><link>/2009/02/why-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 04:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/why-me/</guid><description>Well, obviously since I was going to be playing a bunch of games this week, my xbox just HAD to die. It gave me the red lights, so I went out and bought a new one. I mean, I just got addicted to Assassins Creed and I had just preordered Halo Wars. What timing! I still haven’t transferred everything over yet, but I should be able to do that today. I bought the Elite so I really hope this one lasts.</description></item><item><title>To Do List</title><link>/2009/02/to-do-list/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 05:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/to-do-list/</guid><description>I have many, many things to do this week. Just though I’d get it written down.
Get an eye exam and new glasses Clean up the room and car Sell some stuff on eBay Buy Halo Wars Get my two computers ready to be sold Release Alarm 3.5.5 and begin working on 3.6 Get the interrupt stuff done for senior design. So yeah, I will also be playing plenty of video games to pass my free time.</description></item><item><title>Eve 6 Song</title><link>/2009/02/eve-6-song/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 04:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/eve-6-song/</guid><description>One of my friends told me about this song. It’s awesome. It’s Think Twice by Eve 6. Listen to it if you get a chance.
When all is said and done And dead does he love you The way that I do Breathing in lightning Tonight’s for fighting I feel the hurt so physical
Think twice before you touch my girl Come around I’ll let you feel the burn Think twice before you touch my girl Come around come around no more Think twice before you touch my girl Come around I’ll let you feel the burn Think twice before you touch my girl Come around no more</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.4 Released, Future Plans</title><link>/2008/11/alarm-3-5-4-released-future-plans/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 16:01:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/alarm-3-5-4-released-future-plans/</guid><description>Ok, Alarm 3.5.4 is code-complete and I&amp;rsquo;m planning on releasing it on Friday (or sooner) depending on any regressions or other bugs I find during the next few days. This version contains more bug fixes than I&amp;rsquo;d like to admit to, but here are the major ones:
Random playlist was not properly reordered after adding or removing items. Vista UAC and Limited Accounts. Should work now&amp;hellip;finally! Prevent Windows Update Restart shown on limited accounts even though it can&amp;rsquo;t be set on them.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.3 Released, Alarm 3.1 End of Support</title><link>/2008/10/alarm-3-5-3-released-alarm-3-1-end-of-support/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 16:01:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/alarm-3-5-3-released-alarm-3-1-end-of-support/</guid><description>In Alarm 3.5.3, I have fixed about 7 bugs and added a new feature. I also added about 10 themes.
Also, as of today, Alarm 3.1 is no longer supported to be auto-updated to 3.5. There are way too many files to update every time I release a new version. If you&amp;rsquo;re using 3.1, you should have updated a long time ago!
As a final note, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that I&amp;rsquo;m up to 2800 downloads total among all the websites that host Alarm 3.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.2 Released</title><link>/2008/07/alarm-3-5-2-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 16:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/07/alarm-3-5-2-released/</guid><description>I should be releasing 3.5.2 this weekend with a playlist update and a single bug fix. Check for updates on Sunday.</description></item><item><title>Alarm 3.5.1 Released</title><link>/2008/06/alarm-3-5-1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/06/alarm-3-5-1-released/</guid><description>Ok, so today I released Alarm 3.5.1 which includes 2 bug fixes and a new feature called &amp;ldquo;Quick Alarm&amp;rdquo;. This version also adds support for unprotected WMA files.
Go get it!</description></item></channel></rss>